If I say 'legend' to you, what would you
think? Some people would think of Amitabh Bachchan
and some would think of Bill Gates because they are
legends in their respective industries. Today, PolicyX brings you the
best plans from a legendary insurance company,
and this legend is ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance. Hello and
Namaste, welcome to PolicyX. ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance is a dominant
player in the insurance sector.
ICICI Prudential is known
for its special products, term insurance plans, and endowment plans, which are designed keeping in mind the
different needs of different people in India.
ICICI has a claim settlement ratio of
99.1. Today, we bring you the four
best ICICI Prudential life
insurance plans: ICICI Pru
iProtect Smart,
ICICI Pru iCaret, and ICICI Pru Precious
Life. Let's first talk about ICICI Pru
iProtect Smart. ICICI
Pru iProtect Smart is a top-rated
plan.  This is a pure term plan that
offers
financial protection for your family and also provides
critical illness cover, meaning the
plan covers you against serious illnesses.
Critical illness cover
is a popular benefit among one-in-three customers
because it covers 34 critical illnesses,
meaning if you develop any of the 34 critical illnesses, the
insurance company will cover the expenses.
III Pru I Protect Smart
keeps you covered for up to 99 years. The minimum
policy term for this plan is
5 years. The minimum entry age for this plan is
18 years, and the maximum entry age is 65 years. The
maturity age for this policy is 75 years.
Regarding the sum in short, you
can avail a minimum sum insured of ₹25 lakh and a maximum of ₹
20 crore. The most important feature of this plan is
that it fits within your budget,
as its premiums are quite
affordable. You
can also check the premiums on the Policyx website.  And you
can also compare them. The second best plan is
ICICI Pru iK2. It is
a pure term plan which you
can buy online. Like other insurance plans,
it also provides more protection at affordable rates.
If the
holder unfortunately dies, their family
gets a death benefit under this plan, that is, the
family gets money so that they do
not face any financial pressure.
All the
premiums paid under this plan are eligible for tax-free benefit.
ICICI Pru iK2 basically offers two
benefits. In Option One,
on the death of the policyholder, their nominee gets the sum assured.
In Option Two, if the death is due to natural causes, the sum assured is paid to the
nominee. However, if the death is due to an accident,
an additional sum assured
is paid over the sum assured. You can buy this plan
after 18 years and up to a maximum of 65 years. The
third
best plan of ICICI is ICICI Pru Precious Life.
If you are a policyholder, then you can buy any  If you are
traveling with a critical illness, then this
insurance plan is just for you. The
ICICI Prudential Prescription Life plan
covers certain
pre-existing diseases such as
blood pressure, asthma, hypertension, obesity,
and diabetes. Even if you have recovered from cancer,
this plan keeps you covered.
ICICI Precious Life comes in two options:
Life and Life Plus. Under Life, your
family receives a sum assured after your death.
We have already explained what death benefit means. Under Life
Plus, your family receives
an additional sum assured after your death.
Along with the death benefit, the minimum
entry age for this plan is 18 years, and you can avail this plan up to 65 years.
Talking about the maturity age, the minimum sum assured is 23 years and the
maximum is 70 years. The minimum sum assured in this plan is ₹
2 lakh, and the maximum sum assured is ₹2 lakh.  There is
no limit on the premiums of III Pru Precious Life.
You can pay half-yearly, yearly, and monthly as well.
Last but not the least, the
fourth champion of III is III Pru Life Raksha
Life Akshaya, an ideal protection-oriented
plan that keeps your family covered against
financial insecurity. The policyholder
's nominee
receives an amount after their death under the death benefit. The
free loop period of this plan is 15 to 30 days, which means that
if you are not happy with the plan due to some conditions,
you can also drop the policy,
but you will have to do this within 15 to 30 days.
You can buy this policy after the age of 18, up
to a maximum of 60 years. The
minimum sum insured in this plan is ₹
50,000 and the maximum is ₹5 lakh. The policy
term of III Pru Life Raksha is 5 years, which
means the policy remains active for 5
years. Policyholders can also pay the premiums of this plan
monthly, half-yearly, or quarterly. So,
this was III Pru Life Raksha.  Prudential Life
Insurance keeps
making videos on its Four Champion Plans, one of the best rated plans.
If you
want plan details on any specific topic, please let us
know by commenting. Don't forget to give this
video a
thumbs up. For any doubts, India's
most trusted genuine advisor is
always there for you. You will find the link to visit our website
in the description box.
See you later with a new
plan on policy x Bye-bye and take
care.